afrobella.com 2019-05-20

# Privacy Policy | Afrobella

### Privacy Policy for afrobella.com

### [Disclosures and FTC Guidelines](https://www.afrobella.com/disclosures-and-ftc-guidelines/)

 This privacy policy has been compiled to better serve those who are concerned with how their ‘Personally Identifiable Information’ (PII) is being used online. PII, as described in US privacy law and information security, is information that can be used on its own or with other information to identify, contact, or locate a single person, or to identify an individual in context. Please read this privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we collect, use, protect or otherwise handle your Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with our website.

**I respect your privacy.  **

At afrobella.com, the privacy of our visitors is of extreme importance. This privacy policy document breaks down the types of personal information that is received and collected by afrobella.com and how it is used. **  If you require any more information or have any questions about our privacy policy, please feel free to contact us by email at bella@afrobella.com.**

**What personal information do we collect from the people that visit our blog, website or app?**

We do not collect personal information from visitors of our site.

— We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you.

— Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on your site. Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to your users based on their visit to your sites and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy.

— Afrobella.com makes use of log files. The information inside the log files includes internet protocol ( IP ) addresses, type of browser, Internet Service Provider ( ISP ), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement around the site, and gather demographic information. IP addresses, and other such information are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable.

**When do we collect information?**

We collect information from you when you subscribe to a newsletter, fill out a form or enter information on our site by leaving a comment or entering a giveaway. Various plug-ins used to make the site more efficient, also collect information from you. These include backup plugins, statistics (Google Analytics), contact forms, e-commerce (Zazzle, Amazon), email marketing widgets (e.g. sign up via MailChimp and HelloBar), WordPress reaction plugins, spam plugins like Akismet, which filters spam based on data gathered from users’ reactions, email addresses and IP-addresses; and safety plugins, like Wordfence, which processes IP-addresses and user locations for instance.

**How do we use your information?**

We may use the information we collect from you when you register, make a purchase, sign up for our newsletter, respond to a survey or marketing communication, surf the website, or use certain other site features in the following ways:

**•**  To improve our website in order to better serve you.

**•**  To administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site feature and to make sure the brand sends you the item you have won.

**•**  To send periodic emails regarding your order or other products and services.

**Do we use ‘cookies’?**

Yes. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer’s hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the site’s or service provider’s systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. For instance, we use cookies to help us remember and process the items in your shopping cart. They are also used to help us understand your preferences based on previous or current site activity, which enables us to provide you with improved services. We also use cookies to help us compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future. Cookies help us record user-specific information on which pages the user visits, customizes Web page content based on visitors browser type or other information that the visitor sends via their browser. We may also use trusted third-party services that track this information on our behalf.

— Some of our advertising partners may use cookies and web beacons on our site. Our current advertising partners include SheKnows, Google Adsense, RewardStyle, Commission Junction, and Kontera.

— Subscription is optional and you can unsubscribe to those services at any time. My RSS Feed is automatically sent out via Google Feedburner to those who signed up. Subscribers may have filled out their email or contact information via the contact form, when leaving a comment, or to sign up for newsletters  via HelloBar, Mail Chimp or Feedburner. Each site has their own GDPR policies.

— These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to the advertisements and links that appear on afrobella.com send directly to your browsers. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies ( such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons ) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and / or to personalize the advertising content that you see.

— Afrobella.com has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers.

— You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. Afrobella.com’s privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites.

— If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at your browsers’ website.

—  **You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser settings.  If you turn cookies off, It won’t affect your user experience.**

Giveaway Policy

— Afrobella giveaways are only to residents of the United States of America of adult age. There is no purchase necessary to enter, void where prohibited by law.

— Entrants must be at least 14 years of age, we respect COPPA (Children Online Privacy Protection Act) and there is no marketing to children here.

When a giveaway is posted here, willing participants enter their e mail address. Winners are randomly chosen, and Afrobella contacts you via e mail for your address information. Winners must respond within 4 business days, or another winner will be chosen.

— When you have provided your address information, I personally provide that to the brand fulfilling the giveaway in question, for shipping and prize fulfillment purposes.

— By entering a giveaway, you agree to these rules and my privacy policy, and you certify that you are of age and reside in a country where the giveaway is legal.

— **if you have chosen to enter, after the giveaway has closed and winners have been announced, if you would like me to delete your name from the comments please e mail me at bella@afrobella.com.**

Any personal information collected on this blog is used for giveaway purposes only. I will never sell your information, and it is only shared so that your prize can be delivered.

**Third-party disclosure**

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your Personally Identifiable Information unless we provide users with advance notice. This does not include website hosting partners and other parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or serving our users, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release information if needed to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others’ rights, property or safety.

However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.

**Third-party links**

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third-party products or services on our website. These third-party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

**Google**

Google’s advertising requirements can be summed up by Google’s Advertising Principles. They are put in place to provide a positive experience for users. https://support.google.com/adwordspolicy/answer/1316548?hl=en

We use Google AdSense Advertising on our website. Google, as a third-party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our site. Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to our users based on previous visits to our site and other sites on the Internet. **Users may opt-out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google Ad and Content Network privacy policy.**

**We have implemented the following:**

We, along with third-party vendors such as Google use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookies) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) or other third-party identifiers together to compile data regarding user interactions with ad impressions and other ad service functions as they relate to our website.

**Opting out:**  
Users can set preferences for how Google advertises to you using the Google Ad Settings page. Alternatively, you can opt out by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative Opt Out page or by using the Google Analytics Opt Out Browser add on.

**California Online Privacy Protection Act**

CalOPPA is the first state law in the nation to require commercial websites and online services to post a privacy policy. The law’s reach stretches well beyond California to require any person or company in the United States (and conceivably the world) that operates websites collecting Personally Identifiable Information from California consumers to post a conspicuous privacy policy on its website stating exactly the information being collected and those individuals or companies with whom it is being shared. – See more at: http://consumercal.org/california-online-privacy-protection-act-caloppa/#sthash.0FdRbT51.dpuf

**According to CalOPPA, we agree to the following:**

Users can visit our site anonymously.

Once this privacy policy is created, we will add a link to it on our home page or as a minimum, on the first significant page after entering our website.

Our Privacy Policy link includes the word ‘Privacy’ and can easily be found on the page specified above.

You will be notified of any Privacy Policy changes:

**•**  On our Privacy Policy Page

Can change your personal information:

**•**  By emailing us at bella@afrobella.com

**Does our site allow third-party behavioral tracking?**

We allow third-party behavioral tracking.

**How does our site handle Do Not Track signals?**

We honor Do Not Track signals and Do Not Track, plant cookies, or use advertising when a Do Not Track (DNT) browser mechanism is in place.

**COPPA (Children Online Privacy Protection Act)**

When it comes to the collection of personal information from children under the age of 13 years old, the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) puts parents in control. The Federal Trade Commission, United States’ consumer protection agency, enforces the COPPA Rule, which spells out what operators of websites and online services must do to protect children’s privacy and safety online.

We do not specifically market to children under the age of 13 years old.

**Fair Information Practices**

The Fair Information Practices Principles form the backbone of privacy law in the United States and the concepts they include have played a significant role in the development of data protection laws around the globe. Understanding the Fair Information Practice Principles and how they should be implemented is critical to comply with the various privacy laws that protect personal information.

**In order to be in line with Fair Information Practices we will take the following responsive action, should a data breach occur:**

We will notify the users via in-site notification within 7 business days. We also agree to the Individual Redress Principle which requires that individuals have the right to legally pursue enforceable rights against data collectors and processors who fail to adhere to the law. This principle requires not only that individuals have enforceable rights against data users, but also that individuals have recourse to courts or government agencies to investigate and/or prosecute non-compliance by data processors.

**  If you require any more information or have any questions about our privacy policy, please feel free to contact us by email at bella@afrobella.com. **
